Alexandru Sarpe

Bucharest, Romania

Mobile: +40 727 838 332 E-mail: alexsarpe22@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Linux/Network engineer with more than 12 years of work experience in the telecommunications industry and IT. Extensive background in IP network design (routing/switching), network security (IPSec/GRE/MPLS) and troubleshooting – problem solver. During this period of time I had the opportunity to design, implement and troubleshoot multiple enterprise-scale networking solutions, mostly complex IP/MPLS networks, which were designed to serve thousands of users and services. I had worked with cloud vendors (AWS and GCP) and used their services to meet customers demands.

I also have experience with Linux – servers and services administration (Red Hat, Ubuntu, CentOS). I had to work with Docker and Kubernetes in managing containers and have used Ansible for config automation. I own 3 Networking certifications (1 x Cisco and 2 x Juniper), 2 Security certifications (Juniper and CompTIA). I am also Red Hat certified as RHCSA (Red Hat Certified System Administrator) and AWS certified as AWS Solution Architect.

I am highly motivated. I am constantly learning because I like to stay up-to-date with the technology and the tools that are being used to get the job done. I can focus on what I have to do and I can either work alone or in a team.

SKILLS

- Linux administration (Red Hat, Ubuntu CentOS)
- Virtualization & Cloud (AWS)
- Switching & Routing (BGP, OSPF, IS-IS)
- Network Security (IPSec & MPLS)
- Firewalls (Juniper, Fortigate, Palo Alto)
- Load balancer F5 LTM & APM BigIP
- Juniper GGSN (m120)
- Ericsson vEPG
- DNS configuration (bind)
- Apache, MySQL
- Docker, Kubernetes
- Ansible, Vagrant, Jenkins, Git
- Scripting Bash, Python

- Customer oriented
- Problem solver
- Good analytical skills
- Attention to detail
- Quick learner
- Extremely motivated and focused on performance
- Team player and willing to share knowledge

WORK HISTORY

09/2020 - Present

IoT Cloud PS/IP Solution Architect ERICSSON Telecommunications

- Analyze customer's functional requirements and technical specifications
- Create a clear network architecture for an actionable solution that satisfies both the customer and company objectives
- Prepare design documents and detailed design specifications that are in line with the company strategy and company standards
- Interface between internal teams and customer in order to ensure the quality of the delivery
- Offer support for Sales and Pre-Sales teams by providing information regarding the solutions residing in the design document
- Workshop and knowledge sharing sessions within the team
- Guide trainees by on-job training

11/2017 - 08/2020

<u>IoT Cloud PS/IP Integration Engineer</u> <u>ERICSSON Telecommunications</u>

- I had to implement network configurations designed for onboarding telecom mobile operators, and their enterprises, on Ericsson Device Connectivity Platform Machine-to-Machine communication.
- I also had to implement change requests activities on Juniper M120, MX240, Juniper SRX 5000 Series, F5 LTM & APM BigIP Load-Balancer, Ericsson vEPG, Ericsson RedBack routers.
- Support, test, acceptance and fault management activities.
- Use of JIRA and Confluence tools in order to maintain a proper flow of a project.
- This position also required me to review documentation designed for handover to the NOC department and guide trainees by on-job training.
- Provide remote support and troubleshooting activities for the M2M customers in regards to network related activities.

06/2016 - 10/2017

<u>Technical Project Manager</u> RCS & RDS

- I had to offer Pre-Sales and Post-Sales technical support in regards to implementing complex IP/MPLS network solutions.
- I was involved in designing and implementing custom networking solutions (MPLS VPN Layer 2&3) for customers with over 500 sites
- I had to track and manage every stage of the project (acquisition, on-site installation, configuration, support & acceptance)
- Analyze the customer needs and recommend product and service solutions.
- I had to work in a multi-vendor environment, where I had to configure and troubleshoot equipment like: Cisco ASA, Cisco ISR, Juniper SRX, Fortinet firewall solutions, Palo Alto firewall solutions, Ubiquiti wireless products

10/2012 -05/2016

Senior Network Engineer

RCS & RDS

• Troubleshoot and solve customer network issues, related to a broad number of services (IPv4 and IPv6, PPPoE, BGP, EoMPLS, MPLS L2/L3 VPNs), hosting issues with their webservers.

11/2011 -09/2012

<u>Network Support Engineer</u> <u>Ilink</u>

- My job was to troubleshoot networking issues and offer customer support.
- I had to monitor the IP/MPLS CORE network of the Internet Service Provider.
- Data center operations: installing servers in the racks, cabling, servers configuration etc

EDUCATION

Certifications:

- AWS Solution Architect Associate August 2021 August 2024
- RHCSA Red Hat Certified System Administrator May 2021 May 2024
- CompTIA Security+ Feb 2020 Feb 2023
- Juniper JNCIS-SEC Security Aug 2019 Aug 2022
- Juniper JNCIA-Junos Feb 2019 Feb 2022
- CCNA Cisco Certified Network Associate R&S Jun 2018 Jun 2021

Trainings:

- Juniper Advanced Junos Service Provider Routing (AJSPR)
- Advanced Junos Security (AJSEC)
- Junos Layer 2 VPNs (JL2V)
- Junos Layer 3 VPNs (JL3V)
- F5 Administering BIG-IP, Configuring BIG-IP LTM, Troubleshooting BIG-IP LTM training courses
- Palo Alto Firewall Essentials: Configuration and Management

Languages:

English - Full professional proficiency	
German - Limited working proficiency	
Romanian - Native proficiency	
	 _